uh one of the methods of maintaining
focus is something called time boxing
you may hear about this when somebody
talks about the Pomodoro method which is
named after the Tomato timer idea it's
extremely popular right
now um and the the underlying concept is
very basic you I you outline a chunk of
time for yourself and you outline a task
or two that you want to accomplish
during that time
and then you set a timer and you put it
to someplace you can see it it's
important that you be able to see it and
then during that time you you focus on
that one thing you don't as you know so
as a method of improving Focus you're
focused on that one thing and you like
really you know go at it and then when
the timer goes off you stop you take a
moment you look at you assess it where
you are and you take a break you take a
bile break if you want to uh if you're
doing the Pomodoro method I mean
strictly speaking
they I think it's like 2 I don't even
remember you have to go look it up but I
I just need to tell you that I while I
follow sort of a method of the Pomodoro
method it does not always work for
coding so I think the Pomodoro method is
like 25 uh minutes with five minute
breaks and then a 15-minute break after
four of those and to me that is like far
too great of of of a distraction I I
when I code when I get into an algorithm
or I get into something I need to be in
it for about 45 minutes um I I have a
link someplace in my skill set Twitter
to the study that shows that the the
maximum amount of of attention that a
person can provide is 45 minutes uh I
believe that is a better Pomodoro method
it also works better with the whole you
know hourly cycle kind of thing I can
just kind of I don't even need a timer I
can just go hey for this hour I want to
focus on this one thing um it also works
with um you know the general idea of
scheduling so people will schedule like
a a meeting for an hour for 30 minutes
or something like that so my favorite uh
method of of doing my time box my time
box is about 45 minutes um and then I
usually will take like a really big
break like like 10 or 10 or 15 minutes
and when I take that break I'm usually
doing something that's completely
unrelated to what I was just doing so my
brain
shift um sometimes I'll make myself a
waffle or I'll go get coffee or I'll
I'll I'll talk in the in the in the chat
here and by the way I mean I made
another video on this but co-learning or
co-working this idea of being in the
same room uh with other people that are
working as long as you can do that
without feeling distracted is very
valuable and I will plug the the the the
music co-working videos that I do uh
live streams we just turn on music and
it's like a water cooler particularly
for people who work remotely who want
the feeling of being a part of a
community or something and maybe they
just want to shoot the breeze or they
want to ask a quick question um so
that's a nice thing to do during your
break um you know during that that break
time of a Time boxing method um just to
to show you a couple of ideas here here
is me with the Pomodoro method running
over here uh I've done other videos on
it and if you want to do this I will
show you how to set this up when we set
up t-u uh but this is just a little
command I wrote and go you know bodoro
start you know 45 minutes and it'll
reset um Pomodoro the Pomo stop um and
you know it's just just a fun little
thing I mean I encourage you to actually
make your own it's it's really kind of
fun to make your own little gadgets um
to do this kind of thing and people ask
me all the time well what projects do
you recommend I do I say well you know
make make those fun little things that
you want to make for yourself like a
Twitter a twitch integration or you know
a YouTube API or you know an extra bot
for your for your chat session or a pom
retirement something like that is a
great fun thing to do it's actually
really easy to do um I've even thought
about adding the Pomo project it's a
pretty big project um but we will be
doing coding in JavaScript uh Python and
go this year so uh we might add the Pomo
project to that it's it's a little
bigger than you might anticipate though
there's probably more to it than than
than than if we're just a teeny tiny
project but but it's not too big it's a
fun project to do um H yeah am parer no
we're not going to do that as your first
project so time boxing is the thing give
it a try uh let us know how it works for
you um and see if you can supplement
your your other methods of focus with
time boxing